Day after day, I awake in a daze,
mezamete ha kurikaesu nemui asa ha
目覚めては繰り返す　眠い朝は
And fasten my collar tightly.
eri no tai wo kitsuku shime
襟のタイをきつく締め
As I walk through the door to my classroom,
kyoushitsu no doa kuguru to hon no sukoshi
教室のドアくぐるとほんの少し
I have the slightest bit of pride.
mune wo hatte arukidaseru
胸を張って歩き出せる
Then a wind rushed through that normal, everyday life.
sonna nichijou ni fukinukeru kaze
そんな日常に吹き抜ける風
I have a feeling I can hear it,
kikoeta ki ga shita
聞こえた気がした
I have a feeling I can sense it,
kanjita ki ga shitanda
感じた気がしたんだ
Beginning to tremble within my chest.
furuedasu ima kono mune de
震え出す今この胸で
I have a feeling it's on its way,
mou kuru ki ga shita
もう来る気がした
As the millions of stars began to disappear,
ikuoku no hoshi ga kiesatteku no wo
幾億の星が消え去ってくのを
I sent them on their way,
miokutta
見送った
Waving my hand,
te wo futta
手を振った
Whispering, "Congratulations".
yokatta ne, to
よかったね、と
- 3 Days Later -
ここは…
Where... am I?
どこ？
保健室だ
Health Center (Closed Off)
This is the infirmary.
保健室？
Infirmary?
あなたたち どうしてまだいるの？
Why are you all still here?
Don't push yourself.
無理しちゃダメ
大丈夫よ かなでちゃん
I'm fine, Kanade-chan.
まあ ゆりっぺにしちゃ大変だったようだしな
Well, it looks like it was a challenge even for Yurippe.
よくそんなのでリーダーが務まっていたものだなぁ
I'm amazed you managed to maintain the position of leader for so long.
Even you two?
あなたたちまで…
What are all of you doing here still?
いったい何してるのよ？
影はもういないんじゃないの？
Aren't all the shadows gone?
There shouldn't be anything in your way now.
なら邪魔するものは何もないはず
ああわかってる
Yeah, we know.
Then why?
だったら…
まだ お前が残ってるじゃないか
You're still here.
お前が残ってる
We still need to take care of you.
あ あたし！？
M-Me?!
あっはは そっか
Right...
何て言うんだろ…
W-What should I say to that...?
…何だよ？
What?
多分だけど…
I have a feeling the internal struggle Yuri was suffering has been relieved.
もうゆりの抱えてた葛藤は解けてる
そうなのか？ゆり
It has, Yuri?
えっ！？えと…！それは…その…
Um, well that's...
よし僕が催眠術で吐かせて――
Fine then, I'll use my hypnosis to make her sp-
Don't you dare!
やめろコラァァーーーー！！
と嫌がるということは…
She's so quick to refuse... Looks like it's true.
的中
Huh? No! Th-That's not true.
えっ？　あ いや そんなことないわ…ほら
I-I mean, I'm the leader, so if I were relieved so easily,
I'd be a total laughingstock. You know?
ぁあたしリーダーなのに
そんな簡単に解けちゃってたら　いい笑い草じゃない
ね
じゃあ催眠術でっ！
Then I'll use my hypnosis to-
そうよ解けたわよ！
Fine, it's true! You got a problem with that?!
悪いかぁぁ！！
あ認めた
Ah. She admitted it.
かなでちゃん イジワルなんだ
You're so mean, Kanade-chan.
ゆりがあまのじゃくなだけ
No, you're just obstinate, Yuri.
Thanks...
あなた 言うのね…
でも なんとなく嬉しいな
But that makes me happy, somehow.
What does?
何が？
To hear you call me "Yuri."
ゆりって呼んでくれて
どうして？
Why?
Well, it sounds like we're friends, right?
だって…友達みたいじゃない？
友達
Friends...
You're right.
そうね
んじゃあ準備は無駄にならなかったわけだな
Which means the preparations won't go to waste.
Yeah.
ああ
準備って何か始まるの？
What preparations? Is something happening?
最後にしたいことがあるんだ
There's something we want to do as a last event.
かなで やったことないんだってさ
Apparently Kanade's never experienced it.
え？　何を？
Huh? Experienced what?
Where are the others?
他のみんなは？
They all left.
全員いったよ
そっか良かった
I see. That's great.
This is only possible thanks to everyone's help.
みんなが手伝ってくれたおかげだ
It was one heck of a job.
苦労はしたけどな
ふん神のなせる技だ
Only God could accomplish such deeds.
But you know, despite what everyone said,
they all enjoyed their lives here.
でも 何だかんだ言って
みんなけっこう楽しんでたんだよなここの暮らし
それがわかったぜ
I realised that.
I think it was all thanks to you.
それも ゆりっぺのおかげだと思う
Yeah?
そう
You know, Takamatsu ended up disappearing, too.
高松もいけたんだぜ
He was able to come back to his senses, even after becoming an NPC.
NPCになった後でも正気に戻れたんだ
へーそうなんだ
Oh, really now?
You don't sound too surprised.
あんま驚かないんだな
NPCになったら戻れねぇって言ってなかったっけ？
Wasn't it you who said there would be no turning back after you became an NPC?
想いの強さで いつか人に戻れるようにしてあったのね
I guess the program allows one to return to normal depending on the will of the programmer.
あん
What was that song from?
その歌なんだっけ
You were humming it back when we were setting the stuff up, too.
さっき 作業してる時も口ずさんでたよな？
何だっけ？
What was it...?
I know.
それあれよ
It's the last song Iwasawa-san sang.
岩沢さんが最期に歌った歌
"My Song".
Ah, that song.
あああの曲か
全校放送で流れたやつだな
The one that played on the school's PA system, right? Honestly...
まったく
いい曲よね
It's a nice song, isn't it?
Yes!
うん！
The gym?
体育館？
Yeah.
ああ
Shinda Sekai Sensen Graduation
Afterlife Battlefront Graduation
あぁーー
俺達で作ったんだ
We made it ourselves.
文字はかなで
Kanade did the words.
I see.
そうなんだかなでちゃん 卒業式したことなかったんだ
So Kanade-chan never participated in a graduation ceremony?
おもしろいのかなって
I wanted to know if it's fun.
It's not fun.
おもしろかねぇよぉ
But she looked like she was enjoying it when she was writing the sign.
でも 字を書いてる時は 楽しそうだったけどな
女子はたいてい泣くんだぜぃ
Most girls cry, you know.
ふんこれだから女は
That's why girls are pathetic.
じゃあ 始めよっか
Well, should we get started?
今から
Now?!
何のために着替えたんだよ
Why do you think you got changed?
Well, I was wondering if I'll really disappear.
ぁいや その ホントに消えるのかなって
心の準備が…
And I need to prepare myself a bit, too.
And you're really calling yourself our former leader?
何だそれでも元リーダか
W-What was that?!
な 何よ！
お前 みんなは消えたら
Yeah, you don't seem like a leader at all now that everyone's gone.
りーだーっぽくなくなったよな　なんか
Oh? R-Really?
えっ そ そう？
確かに何か変わったな
Yeah, something is different.
Huh? How?
えっ！どう？
そうだなぁ何か 女の子っぽくなった
Let's see...
I know. You seem more feminine.
Am I supposed to be happy about that? Or angry about that?
それ…喜べばいいの？怒ればいいの？
Now that the battles are over, you've changed back to a pure girl who doesn't even know how to respond to that.
戦い終えたら
そんなこともわからない無垢な女の子に戻っちまったんだな
Yurippe's got a bit of a cute side to her.
ゆりっぺも可愛いとこあんじゃん
あぶ…あぶ あぶ あぶ あぶあばばばばば！！
なが！った！　ったい！　ったい！
ゆり面白いの
Yuri's funny.
よし始めるぞ！
Okay, let's start this!
開式の辞！
Opening statement!
We will now commence the graduation ceremony...
これより 死んだ世界で戦ってきた
死んだ世界戦線の卒業式を執り行います！
...for the members of the Afterlife Battlefront who have been fighting since their deaths!
ではまず 戦歌斉唱！
First, the battle anthem!
戦歌！？　何それ！？
"Battle anthem"? What's that?
死んだ世界戦線の歌だよ
A song for the Afterlife Battlefront. Instead of a school anthem.
校歌の代わりみたいなもの
あたし そんなの作らせた憶えないわよ
I don't remember making anyone come up with that!
それもかなでが作った
Kanade came up with it.
You made one?!
あなたが作ったの？
ってそもそもあなた 戦線じゃないじゃない！
Wait, besides, you're not even part of the Battlefront!
What's the big deal?
いいじゃねぇかはい 歌詞まわして！
はい　歌詞回して
There, pass the lyrics down!
メロディーは？
What's the melody?
校歌って だいたい似たようなもんじゃん？
All school anthems are similar, right?
適当に歌っとけば合うだろ
I think we'll be in harmony even if we wing it.
Ready?
では
せーのっ！
And sing!
"From the world where the sky is dead,"
おそらの死んだー世界からおおくりしーます
"We present to you, our happy-go-lucky selves."
おきらくナンバー
死ぬまでにー くーっとけー
"Before you die, be sure to eat some mapo doufu."
まーぼーどーふ
"Ah, mapo doufu."
あ～あ～～マーボードーフ～
"Mapo doufu."
麻ー婆ー豆ー腐～
って何だよこの歌詞！
What is with these lyrics?!
Somebody should run a check beforehand! I ended up singing it!
先に誰かチェックしとけよ
歌っちまっただろ！
Look, Kanade-chan put some serious thought into it when she wrote it, so you don't have to talk about it like that.
まあ かなでちゃんなりに一生懸命真剣に書いたんだから
そんなに言うことないじゃないねえ？
Right?
"Serious thought"?
「真剣に」って…
I see "happy-go-lucky" written right here.
「お気楽ナンバー」って堂々と書いてあるんだが
Still, how should I put this...
でも 何て言うんだろ
かなでの気持ちが詰まってる気がするよ
It's packed with Kanade's feelings.
Where exactly are they, though?
どこにだよ
They're from the top, down to the bottom.
頭からケツまで
I guess you're right.
そうだな
There you have it, Kanade-chan.
やったね かなでちゃん
うん！
What's next?
次は？
次は…卒業証書授与！
Next...
Diploma presentation ceremony!
We have those?
あるの？
作ったんだよ
We made some.
また主にかなでがな
Mostly by Kanade, again.
っへん！
で 授与する校長は？
Okay, so where's the headmaster to give them to us?
Me!
オレだよ！
Gross...
クソォッ！！　俺がジャンケンで負けたんだよ！
Hey now, I lost in rock paper scissors! You got something to say?!
文句あっか！！
ふん貴様には適任だ
Why am I always the one stuck with these things?!
クソ！　なーんでいっつも俺ばっかりこんな役なんだ！
It's a perfect role for you.
さあ…始めようぜ！
All right... let's begin!
Diploma presentation ceremony!
卒業証書授与！
では…立華かなで！
First, Tachibana Kanade!
Yes!
はい！
Next, Nakamura Yuri!
次仲村ゆり！
Yes!
はい！
それ 似合ってるわよ
You look great in that.
Leave me alone.
ほっとけ
Diploma
Nakamura Yuri
We hereby acknowledge
your full effort
put forth for everyone
at this school.
Afterlife Battlefront
This is silly.
バカ
Next, Naoi Ayato!
次直井文人！
Yes!
はい！
Praise me.
我を称えよ
はぁー？
What the? You da-
ったく
Good work!
お勉め 御苦労さまでした！
Otonashi Yuzuru!
音無結弦
はい！
Yes!
それ取れよ
Take that off.
んじゃあ…
Okay.
Hinata Hideki!
日向ひでき！
あ はい！
Y-Yes!
何だよ…参ったな
Oh, geez...
ありがとな
Thanks.
Same here. You took good care of me.
こちらこそスゲー世話んなった
Representative of the graduating class, your final message!
卒業生代表 答辞！
Ah...
振り返ると いろんなことがありました
Looking back, so much has happened.
この学校で 初めて出会ったのは 仲村ゆりさんでした
The first person I met at this school was Nakamura Yuri-san.
いきなり 死んだのよと説明されました
And the first thing she explained to me was that I was dead.
そして この死後の世界に残っている人達は
Also, I learned that everyone here was unable to accept the life they'd been given and were fighting against God.
皆一様に 自分の生きてきた人生を受け入れられず
神に抗っていることを知りました
私もその一員として戦いました
I fought alongside them as a member.
However, after regaining the memories I had lost, I was able to accept the life I'd had.
しかし 私は失っていた記憶を取り戻すことにより
自分の人生を 受け入れることができました
それは…かけがえのない想いでした
It was a wonderful feeling.
At that point, I wished that everyone could feel that.
それをみんなにも 感じてほしいと思い始めました
ずっと抗ってきた彼らです
They had been fighting all this time.
それはたいへん…難しいことです
It was a hard thing to do.
でも彼らは…助け合うこと 信じあうことができたんです
But they were able to help and trust each other.
The Battlefront that formed around Nakamura Yuri-san had become a group of such wonderful people.
仲村ゆりさんを中心にしてできあがった戦線は
そんな人達の集まりになっていたんです
その力を勇気に…
People started to accept their lives,
changing the group's strength into courage.
みんなは 受け入れ始めました
In the end, everyone was able to look ahead and leave this place.
みんな…最期は 前を見て…立ち去っていきました
ここに残る五名も
The remaining five will graduate from here today, as well.
今日をもって卒業します
一緒に過ごした仲間の顔は忘れてしまっても
Even if I forget the faces of those I spent my time together with,
っ この…魂に刻み合った絆は忘れません
I will not forget the bonds that have been etched on to my soul.
I'm so glad I was able to spend time with you all.
みんなと過ごせて 本当に良かったです！
ありがとうございました！
Thank you so much.
Graduation class speaker, Otonashi Yuzuru!
卒業生代表 音無結弦
All, rise!
全員起立
「仰げば尊し」斉唱！
Sing, "Precious Days."
"We are thankful for all that our teachers have done."
仰ーげばーとうーとしー　我がー師のー恩ー
"We've stayed on this campus for many years."
教ーえのー庭ーにもー　はやー幾ー年ー
"Looking back, they were all such precious days."
思ーえばーいとー疾しー　このー年ー月ー
"Now is the time for our paths to part ways."
今ーこそー別ーれめーーー
いー
"So-"
You're a beat late!
遅いぞ貴様！
What? It was definitely just you who was going too fast!
何！？　明らかにてめぇが早かったろ！
No, you were too slow!
貴様が遅いのが悪いんだろ！
あたしたちは合ってたわよね？
We were in harmony, right?
ホンット音無の時と違うよなお前！
Your attitude is so different with Otonashi!
Ready and-
せーのっ！
"So this is farewell."
いざーさらーーばー
閉式の辞
Closing words!
With this, we will close the Afterlife Battlefront's graduation ceremony.
これをもって
死んだ世界戦線の卒業式を
閉式と致します
卒業生 退場！
Graduating class, dismissed!
I don't want to see the girls cry.
女の泣き顔なんて見たくない
I'll be heading out first.
先に行く
おめぇが泣いてんじゃねぇかよ
You're the one crying.
音無さん…
Otonashi-san.
音無さんに出逢えてなかったら…
If I hadn't met you...
I would never... have been free from my struggle...
僕は…ずっと報われなくて…
But, I...
でもっ 僕は…
もう迷いませんっ
I won't get lost any more.
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
ああ…もういけ
Yeah. Get going now.
ありがとう…ございます
Thank you very much.
There he went.
いったか
さて 次は誰が泣く番だ？
So, who's the next one to cry?
泣きなんてしないわよ！
No one will.
かなでちゃん
Kanade-chan.
うん？
I'm sorry all we did was fight.
争ってばっかりで ごめんね
I really wonder why we couldn't have become friends sooner.
どうしてもっと早く友達になれなかったのかな…
本当にごめんね
I'm really sorry.
ううん
I was the oldest girl in the house, so I looked after
my mischievous siblings like I was their parent.
あたしね 長女でね
やんちゃな妹や弟を 親代わりに面倒見てきたから
So I could have taught you many things.
かなでちゃんにいろんなこと 教えてあげられたんだよ
You looked very unfamiliar with the rest of this world, so I would've taken extra care of you.
かなでちゃん世間知らずっぽいから
余計に心配なんだよ？
いろんなこと…できたのにね
We could have done so many things...
We could have had fun doing so many things...
いろんなことして 遊べたのにね
もっと…もっと…時間があったらいいのにね
If... If only we had more time...
I... I guess this is goodbye.
もう…お別れだね
うん…
Yes.
さようなら…かなでちゃん
Be well, Kanade-chan.
…うん
I will...
じゃあね！
See you.
Yeah, and thanks, Yuri. I'm in your debt.
ああありがとな ゆり
いろいろ世話になりまくった
リーダーお疲れさん
Good work, Leader.
うんじゃあ
We'll meet again somewhere.
またどこかで！
ま俺だわな
Well, I'd say it's my turn, considering the order here.
順番的に言って
いや俺でもいいぜ
No, I can go.
何言ってんだよ
What are you talking about?!
かなでちゃん残して先にいくなよ
Don't leave before Kanade-chan.
I'll go.
俺がいくって
Okay.
そうか
Yeah. I'll go.
ああ俺がいくよ
いろいろありがとな
Thanks for everything.
お前がいなけりゃ何も始まらなかったし
Without you, nothing would have started. We never could have found closure like this.
こんな終わりも迎えられなかった
感謝してる
I'm really grateful.
たまたまだよ
I was lucky.
よく考えたら俺
If you think about it, I had no reason to be here.
ここにくることはなかったんだよな
どういうことだ？
What do you mean?
In the end, my life was a fulfilled one.
俺はちゃんと最後には
報われた人生を送っていたんだ
I found myself in this world because I had forgotten that fact.
その記憶が閉ざされていたから
この世界に迷い込んできた
それを思い出したから
And because I was able to remember, I was able to realise happiness from feeling fulfilled.
報われた人生の気持ちを この世界で知ることができた
そして それを皆にも知ってもらおうと思った
So that's how it went.
そうだったのか
ホントに特別な存在だったんだな お前
You really were a special one, then.
だからみんなの力になれたのも
It was all a chain of luck that I was able to be of help to everyone.
そういう…たまたまのおかげなんだよ
I see.
そっか
まあ長話もなんだ
Well, enough chit-chat.
I'll get going.
じゃ いくわ
Yeah.
ああ会えたら ユイにもよろしく
If you happen to see Yui, say hi for me.
Yeah. I know I saved up my luck, so I'll use everything I've got.
おう運は残しまくってあるはずだからな
使いまくってくるぜ！
おぅし！
Okay!
じゃあな 親友！
See ya, buddy!
えーと…どうだった 卒業式？
So... how was the graduation ceremony?
楽しかったか？
Did you enjoy it?
Yes. Very much.
うんすごく
でも最後は淋しいのね
But it's pretty sad at the end.
But it's the start of a new life.
でも 旅立ちだぜ？
Everyone's off to their new lives. Isn't that a good thing?
みんな…新しい人生に向かって行ったんだ
いいことだろ？
I suppose.
そうね
あのさ 外に出ねぇ？
Hey, why don't we step outside?
ちょっと…風に当たりたいかなって
I want to feel the breeze a little.
ぁ…うん
You know, Kanade.
あのさぁ…かなで
ここに…残らないか？
Would you... like to stay behind?
え？
何か…急に思いついちまった
I thought of it just now, suddenly.
I mean, there will be people who will come to this world, like Hinata and Yuri, having lived unfulfilling lives, right?
だってさ またゆりや日向たちのように
報われない人生を送って
ここにきてしまう奴がいるってことじゃん
You're right.
そうね
They could end up sticking around here like Yuri and the others did.
そいつら またゆりたちのように
ここに居着いちまいかねない
And continue to suffer and resist the opportunities they've been given here.
ここでずっとさぁ
苦しんで 生きることに抗い続けてしまうかもしれない
You're right.
そうね
But if we stayed behind, we could tell them the good part of being here and guide them to graduation.
でもさ
俺たちが残っていたらさ
そいつらに…今回のようにさ
生きることの良さを伝えてさ
卒業させてやることができる
I may have come here to play that role.
もしかしたら…そういう役目のために
俺はここにきたのかもしれない
So...
だからさ一緒に残らないか？
...would you like to stay behind with me?
かなでがいてくれたらさ
If you stay with me, I wouldn't be lonely, even in a world like this.
こんな世界でも 俺は…寂しくないから
前にも言ったかもしれない
I may have said this before, but...
俺はお前と一緒にいたい
...I want to be with you.
これから先も 居続けたい
I want to continue to be with you.
だって俺は…
Because I...
かなでのことが こんなにも…
I just... I love you. So much.
好きだから
I love you.
好きだ
どうして…何も言ってくれないんだ？
Why won't you say anything?
言いたくない
I don't want to answer.
どうして？
Why not?
今の想いを伝えてしまったら…
Because I'd disappear if I were to say what's on my mind right now.
私は 消えてしまうから
どうして？
Why?
Because I came to say "thank you" to you.
だって私は…
ありがとうをあなたに言いに来たんだから
どういうこと だよ？
What do you mean?
I'm the girl whose life you saved, with your heart.
あたしは…
あなたの心臓で…生き永らえることができた女の子なの
今もあたしの胸では
In my chest, right now, your heart is beating.
あなたの心臓が鼓動を打っている
My only regret in life was how I couldn't say
"thank you" to the person who gave my time back to me.
ただ一つのあたしの不幸は
あたしに青春をくれた恩人に
ありがとうを言えなかったこと
That's what I wanted to say... That was the only thing that kept me from fulfilment, and brought me to this world.
それを言いたくて…
If my skirt gets wet,
suso ga nureta nara
裾が濡れたなら
それだけが心残りで
この世界に迷い込んだの
I need only wait until it dries;
kawaku no mateba ii
乾くの待てばいい
You mean...
そんな…でも
But how do you know it was me?
I begin to leap about, surrounded by the sound of water drops.
mizu oto wo tatete haneta
水音をたてて跳ねた
どうして俺だってわかった？
最初の一刺しで気付けた
I realised it when I first stabbed you.
You have no heart.
あなたには…心臓がなかった
You were the one who taught me, and I'm not afraid any more,
kimi ga oshiete kuretanda mou kowakunai
きみが教えてくれたんだ　もう恐くない
でも それだけじゃ
But that's not enough to...
あなたが記憶を取り戻せたのは
The reason why you were able to regain your memory is because you had that dream while lying on my chest.
I have to let go of your supportive hand.
nigitte ite kureta kono te wo hanasanakya dame da
握っていてくれたこの手を離さなきゃだめだ
あたしの胸の上で夢を見たから
You were listening to your own heartbeat.
自分の鼓動の音を 聞き続けていたから
That's...
そんな
I'll move on alone if I have to, even if it's painful,
hitori demo yuku yo tatoe tsurakutemo
ひとりでもゆくよ　例え辛くても
Yuzuru. Please.
結弦お願い
Can you say those words... just once more?
さっきの言葉もう一度言って
I'll keep hold of the dream we all chased together.
minna de mita yume ha kanarazu motteku yo
みんなで見た夢は　必ず持ってくよ
I-I can't...
そんな嫌だ
If I did... you'd disappear!
かなでが消えてしまう！
I loved being with all of you; it's been wonderful,
minna to ga ii na minna to ga yokatta
みんなとがいいな　みんなとがよかった
結弦お願い
Yuzuru! Please!
そんなこと　できない！
Saying it again... I can't!
Yuzuru!
結弦！
But when I wake up in the morning, there's no one here.
demo mezameta asa dare mo inainda ne
でも目覚めた朝　誰も居ないんだね
Please let me believe what you believe in, too.
あなたが信じてきたことを
あたしにも信じさせて
Let me believe that life is wonderful.
生きることは
素晴らしいんだって
Yuzuru.
結弦
かなで
Kanade.
Even if I look behind me, not even a shadow remains,
mou furikaettemo dare no kage mo nai
もう振り返っても誰の影もない
愛してる
I love you.
ずっと一緒にいよう！
Let's always be together.
うんありがとう結弦
Yes... Thank you, Yuzuru.
Only the puddles reflect any light.
mizu tamari dake ga hikatta
水たまりだけが光った
We'll always... always be together!
ずっと…っ ずっと一緒にいようっ！
Yes... Thank you!
うんありがとう
To live is to resist,
ikiteku koto sore ha tachimukatte iku koto
生きてくことそれは立ち向かっていくこと
愛してるかなで！
I love you.
Kanade.
うんすごくありがとう
Yes. Thank you so much.
Kanade...
かなでぇっ！
Once you understand this, all you need is the courage to step forward.
sore ga wakatta nara ato ha fumidasu yuuki dake
それがわかったなら後は踏み出す勇気だけ
愛してくれて ありがとう
Thank you for loving me.
消えないで くれっ！
Don't disappear.
Kanade...
かなで…
Kanade!
かなでぇ…っ！
Thank you... so very much... for giving me life.
命をくれて…
本当にありがとう
I'll go as far as I have to, I learned that fact right here,
doko made mo yuku yo koko de shitta koto
どこまでもゆくよ　ここで知ったこと
I'll show you that I can grant my dream of happiness.
shiawase to iu yume wo kanaete miseru yo
幸せという夢を叶えてみせるよ
Even if we're all separated, no matter the distance,
minna to hanaretemo donna ni tooku nattemo
みんなと離れても　どんなに遠くなっても
Kanade!
かなでぇーーー
When the new morning breaks, I'll go on living.
atarashii asa ni kono boku ha ikiru yo
新しい朝に　この僕は生きるよ
Flowing in and out, time weaves its way,
megutte nagarete toki ha utsuroida
巡って流れて　時は移ろいだ
I can't even remember what's happened to me any more.
mou nani ga atta ka omoidasenai kedo
もう何があったか　思い出せないけど
If I try closing my eyes, I hear the sound of everyone laughing,
me wo tojite mireba minna no waraigoe
目を閉じてみれば　みんなの笑い声
Somehow, right now, that seems like my greatest treasure.
naze ka sore ga ima ichiban no takaramono
なぜかそれが今一番の宝物